Guide to the School of Medicine, Yale University, Records of the Dean
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Medicine, Yale University, records of the dean
1888-1987
RU 285
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
151
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, curriculum materials, subject files, faculty and personnel files, and financial and administrative files of the deans of the Yale School of Medicine. Included are records of deans George Blumer, Milton G. Winternitz, Stanhope Bayne-Jones, Francis G. Blake, Cyril N. H. Long, Vernon W. Lippard, and Robert W. Berliner.
Yale University. School of Medicine
Bayne-Jones, Stanhope, 1888-1970
Berliner, Robert W., 1915-2002
Blake, Francis G. (Francis Gilman), 1887-1952
Blumer, George, 1872-1962
Lippard, Vernon W., 1905-
Long, C. N. H. (Cyril Norman Hugh), 1901-1970
Winternitz, M. C. (Milton C.), 1885-1959
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-A (YRG 27-A), Central records and records of the dean of the Yale School of Medicine.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, curriculum materials, subject files, faculty and personnel files, and financial and administrative files of the deans of the Yale School of Medicine. Included are records of deans George Blumer, Milton G. Winternitz, Stanhope Bayne-Jones, Francis G. Blake, Cyril N. H. Long, Vernon W. Lippard, and Robert W. Berliner.
Medical colleges -- Faculty; Medical colleges; Medicine -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Records of Cyril N. H. Long, 1947-1952; Accession 1955-A-002
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - B (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - C (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - D (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - E (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - F (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - G (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - H (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - I (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - J (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - K (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - L (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - M (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Mc (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - N (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - O (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - P (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Q (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - R (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - S (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - T (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - V (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - W (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - X, Y, Z (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 24 - 26)
- Records of Deans George Blumer, Milton C. Winternitz, Stanhope Bayne-Jones, Francis G. Blake, and Cyril N. H. Long, 1888-1960; Accession 1961-A-002
  Box 119b-120a, 139b-146a, and 156b-163a are restricted until January 1, 2036 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Administration, School of Medicine, 1935-1952 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 6)
  - Administration: Supplies, orders for, 1935-1942 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 9)
  - Admissions, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Board of, 1921-1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - System of, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Trips to other schools, 1949-1952 (Box 1, Folder 13 - 14)
  - Alumni, 1917-1952 (Box 2, Folder 15 - 16)
    - Alumni Board, 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Alumni in Medicine, 1925-1952 (Box 2, Folder 18 - 20)
    - Alumni Notes, other than the School of Medicine, 1937-1942 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Alumni University Day, 1922-1942 (Box 2, Folder 22 - 24)
      - Programs, etc., 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - In American Men of Medicine, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Class of 1931M Suspense Account, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Eugene Bouton, B.A. 1875, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Registrar, 1926-1952 (Box 2, Folder 29 - 31)
    - Reunions, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Class of 1932M, 1937-1952 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Medical, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Yale Alumni Magazine, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Antivivisection, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Applicants for Admission
    - Appointments with Committee on Admissions, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 37 - 38)
    - Black List, Forged Credentials, 1919-1952 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Fees, 1934-1940 (Box 3, Folder 40 - 41)
    - Group Recommendations, 1923-1952 (Box 3, Folder 42 - 46)
    - Inquiries from Students, 1948-1951 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Miscellaneous Procedure, 1941-1952 (Box 4, Folder 48 - 51)
    - Public Health Enquiries, 1941-1943 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Yale Students, Premedical Club, 1948-1952 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Applications, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Statistical Chart of, 1935-1950 (Box 4, Folder 55 - 58)
  - Applications and Miscellaneous Forms, 1956-1952 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Army Student Training Program (ASTP), 1943 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Contract, 1943-1945 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1946 (Box 5, Folder 62 - 64)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Correspondence - Yale AST Headquarters, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Correspondence - Barracks, 1943 April - December (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Correspondence - Yale AST Headquarters, September 1944 June (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Enrollment, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Induction Procedure, 1943 April-December (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Notices to Students, 1913 April-December (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Birth Control, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Board of Permanent Officers - Minutes of the Meetings of, 1932-1931 (Box 5, Folder 73 - 77)
  - Board of Permanent Officers - Mlinutes of the Meetings of, 1937-1946 (Box 6, Folder 78 - 87)
  - Board of Permanent Officers - Minutes of the Meetings of, 1946-1952 (Box 7, Folder 88 - 94)
  - Board of Permanent Officers, 1932-1937 (Box 7, Folder 95 - 97)
  - Board of Permanent Officers (cont'd), 1937-1949 (Box 8, Folder 98 - 107)
  - Board of Permanent Officers, 1949-1952 (Box 9, Folder 108 - 111)
  - Bodies, Requests for Yale to buy, 1935-1946 (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - Book list, 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Book lists for the Physiological Sciences, 1941-1942 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Bookstore, Medical, 1930-1945 (Box 9, Folder 115 - 117)
  - Buildings, undated (Box 10, Folder 118 - 120)
    - Brady Memorial Laboratory, 1912-1915 (Box 10, Folder 121)
      - correspondence with Hospital Architect E.B. Johnson, 1914-1918 (Box 10, Folder 122)
      - Farnam Memorial Building, Formal opening of, 1923-1928 (Box 10, Folder 123)
    - Building Costs, 1928-1940 (Box 10, Folder 124)
    - Building Data, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 125)
    - Building Plans, 1915-1918 (Box 10, Folder 126)
    - Buildings and Repairs, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 127)
    - Dormitory, Proposed, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 128)
    - General Developments, 1922-1926 (Box 10, Folder 129)
    - Hospital, New Haven, Private Pavilion, 1927-1928 (Box 10, Folder 130)
    - Maintenance of Buildings, 1938-1944 (Box 10, Folder 131)
    - Further Units, Financial Program, 1926-1929 (Box 10, Folder 132)
    - Sterling Hall of Medicine, 1920-1923 (Box 10, Folder 133 - 134)
      - Dedication, 1924-1925 (Box 10, Folder 135)
    - Surgery, obstetrics and gynecology, and pathology, 1927-1929 (Box 10, Folder 136)
  - Calendar, 1924-1952 (Box 10, Folder 137)
  - Cancer, 1927-1945 (Box 10, Folder 138 - 139)
    - Malignancy Program, 1928-1933 (Box 10, Folder 140)
    - Material from Dr. Harvey, 1923-1932 (Box 11, Folder 141)
    - Research Projects, 1933-1934 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Cannon Nursery, 1930-1932 (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Catalogue, 1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 144)
    - Entries, 1917-1936 (Box 11, Folder 145)
    - School of Medicine, 1925-1952 (Box 11, Folder 146 - 150)
  - Catalogues, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 151)
  - Child Neurology Research Grant, 1937-1941 (Box 11, Folder 152)
  - Class Material, 1946-1947 (Box 11, Folder 153)
  - Class Schedules: First Year, 1943-1944 (Box 11, Folder 154)
  - Class Secretary, 1943-1955 (Box 11, Folder 155)
  - Clinical Microscopy Laboratory, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 156)
  - Clinical Sciences
    - Clinical Medicine, Department of, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 157)
    - Clinical Practice, Committee on, undated (Box 11, Folder 158)
    - Clincial Sciences, Committee, 1934-1953 (Box 12, Folder 159 - 165)
    - Clinical Subjects, Committee on, 1936-1937 (Box 12, Folder 166)
    - Full Time in Clinical Medicine, Committee on, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 167)
    - Preclinical Sciences, Committee on, 1946-1950 (Box 12, Folder 168 - 169)
  - Clubroom Activities, 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 170)
    - Medical, 1923-1948 (Box 12, Folder 171)
  - Combined Course, 1916-1942 (Box 13, Folder 172 - 173)
    - Sheffield Scientific School, 1915-19 (Box 13, Folder 174 - 175)
    - Yale College, 1904-1923 (Box 13, Folder 176 - 177)
    - With other Universities, 1913-1921 (Box 13, Folder 178)
  - Combined Courses, 1942-1950 (Box 13, Folder 179)
  - Commencement, 1928-1940 (Box 13, Folder 180 - 182)
  - Commencement, 1941-1952 (Box 14, Folder 183 - 190)
  - Committee on
    - Administrative Functions, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 191)
    - Admissions, 1935-1940 (Box 14, Folder 192 - 196)
    - Admissions, 1940-1952 (Box 15, Folder 197 - 200)
    - Anatomy; the Development of at Yale, 1932-'33 (Box 15, Folder 201)
    - Animal Experimentation, 1936-1937 (Box 15, Folder 202)
    - Appointments, 1931-1932 (Box 15, Folder 203)
    - Awards and Prizes, 1939-1942 (Box 15, Folder 204)
    - Biological Laboratory, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 205)
    - Biological Sciences, 1932-1936 (Box 15, Folder 206 - 207)
    - Biometry, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 208)
    - Catalogue, 1934-1938 (Box 15, Folder 209)
    - Clinical Subjects, 1931-1949 (Box 15, Folder 210 - 211)
    - Cost of Medical Care, 1927-1933 (Box 15, Folder 212)
    - Curriculum, 1914-1941 (Box 15, Folder 213 - 216)
    - Deanship and Administrative Organization of the School of Medicine, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 217)
    - Division of Biological Sciences, Executive Committee, 1940-1945 (Box 16, Folder 218 - 220)
    - Educational Policy
      - Provost, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 221)
      - Yale Corporation, 1935-1937 (Box 16, Folder 222)
    - Executive, 1929-1947 (Box 16, Folder 223 - 229)
    - Executive, 1947-1952 (Box 17, Folder 230 - 239)
      - Hospital Fundraising, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 240)
    - Faculty of the First Two Years: Minutes, 1915-1919 (Box 17, Folder 241)
    - Full Time in Clinical Medicine, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 242)
    - Graduate and Professional Schools, 1953-1955 (Box 17, Folder 243)
    - Medical Student Health, 1949-1952 (Box 17, Folder 244)
    - Miscellaneous, 1934-1948 (Box 17, Folder 245)
    - New Medical School Buildings, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 246)
    - Committee Organization, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 247)
    - Pharmacology, 1932-1936 (Box 17, Folder 248)
    - Portrait, 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 249)
    - Preclinical, 1931-1940 (Box 18, Folder 250 - 259)
    - Preclinical, 1937-1944 (Box 19, Folder 260 - 266)
    - Preclinical Subjects, 1948-1952 (Box 19, Folder 267 - 269)
    - Prizes'and Awards, 1931-1942 (Box 20, Folder 270 - 274)
    - Professorship of Physiological Chemistry, 1935-1936 (Box 20, Folder 275)
    - Program and Policy, 1940-1945 (Box 20, Folder 276 - 277)
    - Promotions and Appointments, 1950-1951 (Box 20, Folder 278)
    - Psychological Methods in Examinations, 1919 (Box 20, Folder 279)
    - Public Health, 1933-1938 (Box 20, Folder 280 - 283)
    - Public Health, 1938-1947 (Box 21, Folder 284 - 290)
    - Qualifying Examination, 1936-1942 (Box 21, Folder 291 - 292)
    - Relationship between the Hospital, the Dispensary, and the Medical School, undated (Box 21, Folder 293)
    - Requirerments for Admission, 1942 (Box 21, Folder 294)
    - School of Medicine, 1932-1936 (Box 21, Folder 295 - 297)
    - Science and Engineering, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 298)
    - Student Affairs, 1945-1952 (Box 22, Folder 299 - 300)
    - Student Health, 1930-1941 (Box 22, Folder 301 - 302)
    - University Development, The President's, 1940 (Box 22, Folder 303)
  - Committees, 1911-1952 (Box 22, Folder 304 - 309)
    - Board for the Investigation of Epidemic Diseases in the United States Army, 1942-1945 (Box 22, Folder 310)
    - Commissions on Epidemiological Survey, w709ad-19466, 1943-1944 (Box 22, Folder 311)
    - Commission on Infantile Paralysis, 1915-1919 (Box 22, Folder 312)
    - Commission on Neurotropic Virus Diseases, 1943-1945 (Box 22, Folder 313)
    - Minutes and Membership of Committees, 1933-1935 (Box 22, Folder 314)
  - Conferences
    - Deans, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 315)
    - Harvard Club of Boston: Symposium on "Medicine and Life Today", 1938 (Box 23, Folder 316)
    - Maternal Health, 1932-1936 (Box 23, Folder 317)
    - St. Louis, 1926 (Box 23, Folder 318)
    - White House: Winternitz, 1930-1931 (Box 23, Folder 319)
  - Course: Five Year, 1914-1916 (Box 23, Folder 320)
  - Culture Media, 1929-1933 (Box 23, Folder 321)
  - Curriculum, 1919-1947 (Box 23, Folder 322 - 323)
    - Education
      - Graduate Medical, 1931-1936 (Box 23, Folder 324)
      - Medical, 1897-1942 (Box 23, Folder 325 - 327)
      - Pre-Medical, 1915-1936 (Box 23, Folder 328)
    - Graduate Medical Instruction, 1924-1939 (Box 23, Folder 329 - 331)
    - Graduate Medical Instruction, 1929-1952 (Box 24, Folder 332 - 335)
    - Medical, 1911-1942 (Box 24, Folder 336 - 342)
    - Medical, 1941-1952 (Box 25, Folder 343 - 344)
    - Premedical, 1927-1944 (Box 25, Folder 345 - 348)
  - Deafness Project: Appeal for Funds, Unsuccessful, 1939-1940 (Box 25, Folder 349)
  - Deanship
    - Bayne-Jones, 1935-1938 (Box 25, Folder 350)
      - Resignation of, 1940 (Box 25, Folder 351)
    - Blake, Francis G., 1940 (Box 25, Folder 352)
  - Deanship, Assistant, 1943-1943 (Box 25, Folder 353)
    - Smith, Dr. George H., 1940 (Box 25, Folder 354)
  - Degrees, 1936-1938 (Box 25, Folder 355)
  - Dentistry, 1930-1940 (Box 25, Folder 356)
  - Departmental Correspondence
    - Anatomy, Department of, 1915-1952 (Box 26, Folder 357 - 360)
      - Miscellaneous, 1922-1941 (Box 26, Folder 361)
      - Staff, 1928-1943 (Box 26, Folder 362)
      - Correspondence, Courses, 1931-1942 (Box 26, Folder 363)
      - Section of Neuro-anatomy, 1931-1939 (Box 26, Folder 364 - 365)
    - Animal Farm Proposal, 1932 (Box 26, Folder 366)
    - Animals, 1919-1939 (Box 26, Folder 367 - 369)
      - Accomodations for care of, 1940-1951 (Box 26, Folder 370)
      - Animal Experimentation, 1929-1947 (Box 26, Folder 371)
      - Animal Food, 1939-1947 (Box 26, Folder 372)
      - Animal House: Connnittee on, 1922-1928 (Box 26, Folder 373)
      - Animal House, 1928-1935 (Box 26, Folder 374)
      - Dog Kennel License and Tags, 1929-1942 (Box 26, Folder 375)
      - Dog and Cat Fund, 1919-1926 (Box 26, Folder 376)
      - Dogs, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 377)
      - Dog Legislation, See also: Vivisection, 1927-1936 (Box 27, Folder 378)
      - Monkeys - supply, 1938-1940 (Box 27, Folder 379)
      - Official Reports of the Administration of the Sterling Animal House, 1927-1940 (Box 27, Folder 380 - 381)
      - Pathology, 1925-1927 (Box 27, Folder 382)
      - Project no. 19 - Animal House, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 383)
      - Vivisection, 1938-1939 (Box 27, Folder 384)
    - Bacteriology, Department of: General - Dr. Leo F. Rettger, 1922-1924 (Box 27, Folder 385)
    - Bacteriology, Department of, 1928-1950 (Box 27, Folder 386 - 391)
      - Dr. Bayne Jones, 1933-1942 (Box 27, Folder 392)
    - Bacteriology and Immunology, Department of See also: Immunology, Department of, 1919-1940 (Box 27, Folder 393 - 394)
    - Bacteriology, Pathology and Public Health, 1931-1932 (Box 27, Folder 395)
    - Biological Sciences, Division of, 1939-1940 (Box 28, Folder 396)
    - Clinic of Child Development, Department of, undated (Box 28, Folder 397)
    - Culture Media, Department of, 1928 (Box 28, Folder 398)
    - Culture Media, Division of, 1938-1940 (Box 28, Folder 399)
    - History of Medicine, Department of, 1951 (Box 28, Folder 400)
    - Immunology, Department of See also: Bacteriology, 1928-1942 (Box 28, Folder 401 - 403)
    - Internal Medicine, Department of, 1918-1929 (Box 28, Folder 404 - 405)
      - Annual Reports, 1923-1937 (Box 28, Folder 406)
      - Organization, 1912? (Box 28, Folder 407)
      - Section of Oncology, 1950-1951 (Box 28, Folder 408)
    - Medicine, Department of, 1930-1942 (Box 28, Folder 409 - 410)
    - Mental Hygiene and Psychiatry
      - Lectures
        - Boston Psychopathic Hospital, 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 411)
        - Endocrinology, 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 412)
        - Etiology of Mental Illness, 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 413)
        - "Feeblemindness", 1926-1929 (Box 28, Folder 414)
        - "Manic-Depressive", 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 415)
        - "Mental Hygiene", 1926-1929 (Box 28, Folder 416 - 417)
        - "Physiology, Psychiatry and Inhibitions", 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 418)
        - "Points of Contact between Psychiatry, Internal Medicine and Neurology", 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 419)
        - "Problems in the Pre-School", 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 420)
        - "Psychiatric Symptomatology and Mechanisms", 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 421)
        - "Psychiatry and the Criminal Law", 1926-1929 (Box 28, Folder 422)
        - "Psychiatry, Psychopathology and Mental Hygiene", 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 423)
        - "The Psychoanalytical Approach", 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 424)
        - "Psychology of the Normal Child", 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 425)
        - "Psycho-pathology of Childhood", 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 426)
        - "Speech Disorders", 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 427)
        - "Toxic Psychiatric Reactions", 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 428)
    - Neurology, 1925-1933 (Box 29, Folder 429)
    - Neurophysiology, Department of
      - A, 1938-1940 (Box 29, Folder 430)
      - B, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 431)
      - Budgets, 1930-1940 (Box 29, Folder 432)
      - Bureau of Purchases and Stores, 1934-1941 (Box 29, Folder 433)
      - C, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 434)
      - Dr. Campell, 1939-1940 (Box 29, Folder 435)
      - Chamberlain, Hillard B., 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 436)
      - Re: Chamberlain, 1941 (Box 29, Folder 437)
      - Courses, School of Medicine, 1940 (Box 29, Folder 438)
      - D, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 439)
      - Dean Bayne-Jones, 1939-1940 (Box 29, Folder 440)
      - E, 1940 (Box 29, Folder 441)
      - F, 1941 (Box 29, Folder 442)
      - Feeding Schedules, 1936-1937 (Box 29, Folder 443)
      - Fellowships, Grants, etc., 1933-1939 (Box 29, Folder 444)
      - Friedson Foundation, 1938-1939 (Box 29, Folder 445)
      - G, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 446)
      - H, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 447)
      - Hamilton, John M., 1938-1941 (Box 29, Folder 448)
      - Histological Techniques, undated (Box 29, Folder 449)
      - I, 1937-1940 (Box 29, Folder 450)
      - Importations, Directions for, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 451)
      - J, 1938-1940 (Box 29, Folder 452)
      - Journals and Associations, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 453)
      - K, 1938-1939 (Box 29, Folder 454)
      - L, 1938-1941 (Box 29, Folder 455)
      - M (1 of 2), 1940 (Box 29, Folder 456)
      - M (2 of 2), 1938-1940 (Box 29, Folder 457)
      - John and Mary Harkle Foundation, 1938-1941 (Box 29, Folder 458)
      - Medical -School, 1934-1938 (Box 29, Folder 459)
      - Method-Blain Cast, undated (Box 29, Folder 460)
      - Medical Library, 1931-1939 (Box 29, Folder 461)
      - Monkeys and Other Animals, 1931-1941 (Box 29, Folder 462)
      - N, 1940 (Box 29, Folder 463)
      - Neurological Study Unit, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 464)
      - Neurophysiology, 1935-1942 (Box 29, Folder 465 - 467)
      - O, 1938-1939 (Box 29, Folder 468)
      - P, 1939-1940 (Box 29, Folder 469)
      - U, 1938-1939 (Box 29, Folder 470)
      - Yale Graduate School, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 471)
    - Neurophysiology, Laboratory of, 1930-1941 (Box 30, Folder 472 - 478)
    - Nursing
      - Costs, 1923-1933 (Box 30, Folder 479)
      - Connecticut Training School for Nurses, 1913-19 (Box 30, Folder 480 - 481)
      - Reprints, 1926-1939 (Box 30, Folder 482)
      - School of - Yale, 1924-1941 (Box 30, Folder 483 - 486)
        - Clippings and Releases, 1929-1935 (Box 30, Folder 487)
        - Committee for Survey of Educational Policies; Cost of Instruction; Nursing Service and the Hospital, 1923-1935 (Box 30, Folder 488)
      - Visting Nurse Association, 1917-1930 (Box 31, Folder 489 - 490)
    - Obstetrics and Gynecology, Department of, 1916-1952 (Box 31, Folder 491 - 496)
      - Budgets, 1921-1937 (Box 31, Folder 497)
      - Research Fund, 1930-1934 (Box 31, Folder 498)
    - Oral Pathology, Department of
      - Connecticut State Dental Association, 1936-1940 (Box 31, Folder 499)
      - Dental Clinic Society, 1933-1943 (Box 31, Folder 500 - 501)
      - Dental Lectures, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 502)
      - Dental Research, 1934-1950 (Box 31, Folder 503 - 505)
      - Department of Oral Pathology - Dental, 1923-1935 (Box 31, Folder 506 - 509)
      - Dental Study Expenditures, 1930 (Box 32, Folder 510)
      - Founding Documents, 1894-95 (Box 32, Folder 511)
      - General Correspondence, 1924-1935 (Box 32, Folder 512 - 513)
      - Hospital - Dental Clinic, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 514)
      - Memoranda, 1927-1935 (Box 32, Folder 515)
      - Public Education, 1934-1938 (Box 32, Folder 516)
      - Purcell, Joseph Research Memorial Fund, 1938-1946 (Box 32, Folder 517)
      - Stomatology Movement, 1933 (Box 32, Folder 518)
      - Yale Dental Program, 1930-1937 (Box 32, Folder 519 - 522)
    - Otolaryngology, Section of Department of Surgery, 1934-1946 (Box 32, Folder 523)
    - Pathology, Department of, 1917-1942 (Box 32, Folder 524 - 528)
    - Pathology, Department of, 1935-1952 (Box 33, Folder 529 - 536)
      - Budgets, 1919~37 (Box 33, Folder 537)
      - Reports to the Dean, 1927-1933 (Box 33, Folder 538)
      - Section of Neuropathology, 1933-1939 (Box 33, Folder 539 - 540)
    - Pediatrics, Department of, 1914-1935 (Box 33, Folder 541 - 546)
    - Pediatrics, Department of, 1930-1952 (Box 34, Folder 547 - 554)
      - Organization, 1920-1927 (Box 34, Folder 555)
      - Pediatric-Psychiatry and Preschool Studies in a Nursery Clinic: current, 1938-1939 (Box 34, Folder 556)
      - Reports, 1921-1934 (Box 34, Folder 557)
    - Pharmacology, Department of, 1920-1952 (Box 34, Folder 558 - 563)
    - Pharmacology and Toxicology, Department of, 1924-1940 (Box 35, Folder 564 - 573)
    - Photographic Laboratory, 1935-1952 (Box 35, Folder 574 - 577)
    - Photography, Department of, 1924-1933 (Box 35, Folder 578)
    - Photography, Division, 1928-1938 (Box 35, Folder 579)
    - Photography, Section of, 1936-1939 (Box 35, Folder 580)
    - Physical Therapy, Division of, 1928-1938 (Box 35, Folder 581 - 583)
    - Physical Therapy, Section of, 1928-1940 (Box 35, Folder 584)
    - Physiological Chemistry, Department of, 1915-1949 (Box 36, Folder 585 - 591)
    - Physiological Chemistry and Pharmacology, Department of, 1928-1941 (Box 36, Folder 592)
    - Physicological Psychology, Department of, 1937-1940 (Box 36, Folder 593)
    - Physiological Sciences, Department of, 1932-1938 (Box 36, Folder 594)
    - Physiology, Department of, 1917-1942 (Box 36, Folder 595 - 603)
    - Physiology, Department of, 1938-1952 (Box 37, Folder 604 - 606)
      - Budgets, 1916-1936 (Box 37, Folder 607)
      - Personnel, 1926-1929 (Box 37, Folder 608)
    - Physiology, Laboratory of, 1936-1939 (Box 37, Folder 609 - 611)
    - Preventive Medicine, 1946-1952 (Box 37, Folder 612)
      - Committee on, 1925-1934 (Box 37, Folder 613)
      - Section of, 1940-1946 (Box 37, Folder 614 - 615)
    - Primate Biology, Yale Laboratories of, 1936-1951 (Box 37, Folder 616 - 621)